Guide to the Chit Chat Club Records, 1877-2010 M0158
Dept. of Special Collections & University Archives
Chit Chat Club Records
1877-2013
M0158
Dept. of Special Collections & University Archives
8.0 Linear feet
Chit Chat Club
Historical Note
The Chit Chat Club was founded in 1874 in San Francisco. It is a private essay club whose 25 members meet the second Monday of each month to hear and discuss an essay written by one of its members.
Scope and Content
Records of the Chit Chat Club of San Francisco including correspondence, essays, biographical, administrative and related material.
Provenance
Gift of San Francisco Literary Club, 1966, and the Chit Chat Club, 1984, 1985, 1986, 1991, 1995, 1997, 2002, 2003, 2005, 2007, 2008, 2009, 2010.
Access Restrictions
None.
- Series I. Correspondence and Related Material
  - Correspondence, etc., 1879-1939 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Scope and Contents note
    H.W. Bellows, Chas. A. Murdock, J. Hasbrouck, F.W. Tompkins, Horatio Stebbins (art.), Sheldon G. Kellogg, Eli T. Sheppard (art.), misc. (Regular Republican League) Edward Robeson Taylor, M.C. Sloss, Douglas W. Montgomery, M.W. Haskell, Walter Morris Hart, Warren C. Perry, Chauncey D. Leake (unsigned)
  - Correspondence, etc., 1940-1944 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    Curtis D. Wilbur, O.L. Elliott, J.S. Hutchinson, Wm. E. Colby, Dorothy Farrell, Edgar E. Ribinson, Edward L. Parsons, J.B. Candliffe, Emma Alsborg, C.A. Duireway, Chauncey D. Leake, C.D. Shane, M.W. Haskell, Edwin A. Cottrell, Arthur W. Parsons, Godfrey A. Fisher, Gilbert N. Lewis, M.C. Sloss, Robert M. Searls, Walter Morris Hart, Paul C. Edwards, Wm. Denman, Langley Porter, Chester H. Rowell George J. [Peirce], Maurice E. Harrison
  - Correspondence, 1945-1949 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    George J. Peirce, Chauncey D. Leake, Joel H. Hildebrand, Ben. C. Duniway, M.C. Sloss, Robert M. Searls, Walter Morris Hart, Godfrey A. Fisher, Langley Porter, Curtis D. Wilbur, C.D. Shane, M.K, Bennett, James W. Mc Bain, Mary H. (Mrs. Gilbert N.) Lewis, Salvatore Pablo Lucia, Maurice E. Harrison, Herbert F. Trant, Francis P. Farquhar, Edwin A. Cottrell, Edward L. Parsons, Wm. E. Colby, Wm. Denman, Cyril H. Cane, Ronald Bridges, Mellen W. Haskell, Isabel Haskell, Elton Trueblood, Edgar E. Robinson, Murray Richards, Joseph T. O'Connor, Alex. Johnson, Harold Bradley, Robert Mc. Williams, Rabb Minto, E. Kenneth Smart, William Palmer Lucas, Frederick, Thompson, Raymond G. [Gettell], Alexander Meiklejohn, Richard Glenn Gettell, Osgood Murdock, (unsigned)
  - Correspondence, 1950-1953 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    Chauncey D. Leake, Osgood Murdock, Edgar M. [UNK] Rabb Minto, Wm. Denman, Salvatore P. Lucia, Langley Porter, Dixon Wecter, John R. May, Lloyd D. Luckmann, Robert M. Searls, Paul C. Edwards, M.K. Bennet, Murray Richards Walter Morris Hart, Ben C. Duniway, Alex. Meiklejohn, Edward L. Parsons, Joseph T. O'Connor, C. Donald Shane, Book Club of Calif., George J. Peirce, Carl I. Wheat, Mary Lea Shane, J.B. Condliffe, Harold H. Fisher, Ira B. Joraleman, Edgar [UNK] Robinson, Gertrude Searls, Wm. Kuder, H. Lissner, Richard H. Dillon, John Barr Tompkins
  - Correspondence, 1957-1959 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    Chauncey D. [UNK], Salvatore P. Lucia, [UNK] Murdock, Rabb Minto, Wm. Denman, Edward L. Parsons, Nat Schmulowitz, Edgar [UNK] Robinson, Stanford University Libraries, Walter Morris Hart, Bancroft Library, Frederick Barreda Sherman, Langley Porter, Harold H. Fisher, Alexander Meiklejohn, Edgar M. Kahn, Edith Murdock Williams, Dorothy M. Danna, Margaret Murdock, Paul C. Edwards, C.D. Shane, (HO HO background), H.S. Marchant, Radioscript by Tom Groody, J.B. deC.M. Saunders, J.B. [UNK] Ruth A. O'Connor, Marcel Rijmenans, secretary's report, Murray Richards (unsigned)
  - Correspondence, 1960-1969 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    Langley Porter, Rabb Minto, University Club, Oswald G. Villard, Jr., Frank H. Sloss, Wm. Marchant, Walter Morris Hart, J.B. deC.M. Saunders, Wm. B. Kuder, Frank Gerbode, Harriet T. Parsons, Paul C. Edwards, Alex. Meiklejohn, C. [UNK] Bartlett, Chauncey D. Leake, Salvatore P. [UNK], Wm. C. Bark, Edgar [UNK]. Robinson, Murray Richards, Ben C. Duniway, lists of essays, alphabetical list of members
  - Correspondence, Osgood Murdock file (Chit Chat Club secretary), 1953-1957 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    mostly correspondence C. [UNK], Edward L. Parsons, Frank H. Sloss, Carl I. Wheat, Chauncey D. Leake, Edgar [UNK] Robinson, Harold H. Eisher, Frank Gerbode, John R. May, [UNK] H. Hildebrand, University Club, Alex. Meiklejohn, Ben C. Duniway, Paul C. Edwards, Walter Morris Hart, J.B. Condliffe, Langley Porter, Osgood Murdock, Lucy Mc Williams, Elton [UNK], Worldover Importers Inc., Wm. Denman, Salvatore P. Lucia, Wm. E. Colby, Calif. State Library (A.R. Ottley), Leslie E. Bliss (Huntington Library), James de T. Abajian (Calif. Historical Society), Lawrence Kinnaird ([UNK] Library), Wm. B. Kuder, Joseph T. O'Connor, Rosamond Peirce, D. Melrose
  - Correspondence, 1976-1982 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence, 1978 (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence, 1981-1984 (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, 1981-1984 (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence, 1985-1986 (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence files, 1987-1990 (Box 15, Item 14)
  - Correspondence files, 1975-1983 (Box 15, Folder 15)
  - Correspondence files, 1984-1986 (Box 15, Folder 16)
  - Correspondence files, 1991-1993 (Box 15, Folder 17)
  - Correspondence, 1996-2005 (Box 16, Folder 18)
  - Correspondence, 2009 (Box 17, Folder 1)
- Series II. Essays
  - Chit Chat Club essays and miscellaneous, Edgar M. Kahn file, 1941-1965 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Chit Chat Essays, 1884 (Box 2, Volume 1)
    Small bound volume of printed essays.
    - George Eliot, Gordon Blanding, July 9, 1877 (Box 2, Volume 1, Item 1)
    - Montaigne, John C. Hall, Jun 18, 1883 (Box 2, Volume 1, Item 2)
    - A Banquet at Peterhoff: A Historical Study, Samuel Bradley Wiggin, Aug. 13, 1883 (Box 2, Volume 1, Item 3)
    - The Policy of Protection, Charles A. Murdock, 1884 (Box 2, Volume 1, Item 4)
  - Chit Chat Essays, 1927-1945 (Box 2, Volume 2)
    Bound volume of typescripts, draft signed, and reprints of essays.
    - Italy and Fascismo, Orrin Leslie Elliot, 1927 (Box 2, Volume 2, Item 1)
    - The US As A World Power, Raymond C. Gettell, 1929 (Box 2, Volume 2, Item 2)
    - Illinois to Oregon in 1952, Clyde A. Duniway, 1940 (Box 2, Volume 2, Item 3)
    - Early Days of the Chit-Chat Club, Langley Porter, 1941 (Box 2, Volume 2, Item 4)
    - Civil Liberties in War Time, Edward L. Parsons, 1942 (Box 2, Volume 2, Item 5)
    - Land of Promise -- How Fare our Farmers, Osgood Murdock, 1942 (Box 2, Volume 2, Item 6)
    - Ethicogenesis, Chauncey D. Leake, 1942 (Box 2, Volume 2, Item 7)
    - What Is History? Edgar E. Robinson, 1942 (Box 2, Volume 2, Item 8)
    - The Truth About Education, D. Elton Trueblood, 1943 (Box 2, Volume 2, Item 9)
    - The Churches and the Postwar World, Edward L. Parsons, 1943 (Box 2, Volume 2, Item 10)
    - Who's Boss? Management Now and Tomorrow, Osgood Murdock, 1944 (Box 2, Volume 2, Item 11)
    - Shall We Have Universities? Edgar E. Robinson, 1944 (Box 2, Volume 2, Item 12)
    - The Business of Peace, John B. Condliffe, 1944 (Box 2, Volume 2, Item 13)
    - What is a Dollar? Francis P. Farquhar, 1945 (Box 2, Volume 2, Item 14)
    - Botany: Mother of Science, George J. Pierce, 1945 (Box 2, Volume 2, Item 15)
    - Freedom: What is it? How Do We Get It? Edward L. Parsons, 1945 (Box 2, Volume 2, Item 16)
  - Chit Chat Essays, 1943-1950 (Box 2, Volume 3)
    Bound volume of typescripts, draft signed, and reprints of essays, clippings and misc.
    - The Changing East, John B. Condliffe, 1943 (Box 2, Volume 3, Item 1)
    - Some Impressions of Italy under Fascism, Godfrey A. Fisher, 1945 (Box 2, Volume 3, Item 2)
    - Comments on the Manhattan Project, C. Donald Shane, 1946 (Box 2, Volume 3, Item 3)
    - How Fervid the Church? Osgood Murdock, 1946 (Box 2, Volume 3, Item 4)
    - Russian-American Relations, Robert H. Searles, 1946 (Box 2, Volume 3, Item 5)
    - Fact and Fancy in the Spirit of Wine, Salvatore Pablo Lucca, 1946 (Box 2, Volume 3, Item 6)
    - On Freedom and Value Judgments, Merrill K. Bennett, 1946 (Box 2, Volume 3, Item 7)
    - The Progress of Creation, John B. Condliffe, 1947 (Box 2, Volume 3, Item 8)
    - A Free and Responsible Press, Paul C. Edwards, 1947 (Box 2, Volume 3, Item 9)
    - Am I My Brother’s Keeper, George J. Peirce, 1947 (Box 2, Volume 3, Item 10)
    - Reminiscences of Long Ago, Edward L. Parsons, 1947 (Box 2, Volume 3, Item 11)
    - Dynamic Personalities and their Influence in Directing the Course of Civilization, William P. Lucas, 1947 (Box 2, Volume 3, Item 12)
    - The Scientist and Society, C. Donald Shane, 1948 (Box 2, Volume 3, Item 13)
    - The Business Man in Post War America, Osgood Murdock, 1948 (Box 2, Volume 3, Item 14)
    - Andy Fureseth, Abe Lincoln of the Worlds' Seamen, Wm. Denman, 1948 (Box 2, Volume 3, Item 15)
    - Some Philosophical Reflections on the Law, Robert Searls, 1948 (Box 2, Volume 3, Item 16)
    - The Theriaca, Salvatore Pablo Lucia, 1948 (Box 2, Volume 3, Item 17)
    - Population and Food Supply, M. K. Bennett, 1948 (Box 2, Volume 3, Item 18)
    - Family Disintegration and the Law, Benjamin C. Duniway, 1948 (Box 2, Volume 3, Item 19)
    - The Background of Delinquency, Langley Porter, 1949 (Box 2, Volume 3, Item 20)
    - Responsibility and No Power, George J. Peirce, 1949 (Box 2, Volume 3, Item 21)
    - In the Beginning, C. Donald Shane, 1949 (Box 2, Volume 3, Item 22)
    - Salesmen and Society, Osgood Murdock, 1950 (Box 2, Volume 3, Item 23)
    - Food and Agriculture in the Soviet Union, M. K. Bennett, 1950 (Box 2, Volume 3, Item 24)
    - The Unbalance of Our World, John B. Condliffe, 1950 (Box 2, Volume 3, Item 25)
    - Free Circulation of Gold Its Probable Effect on Our Economic System, Robert M. Searls, 1950 (Box 2, Volume 3, Item 26)
  - Chit Chat Essays, 1950-1954 (Box 3, Volume 1)
    Bound volume of typescripts, draft signed, reprints of essays and some misc. material.
    - The Realization of an Idea- Fairfax H. Wheeler, Charles A. Murdock, 1922 (Box 3, Volume 1, Item 1)
    - Racial Minorities in the United States, William Denman, 1950 (Box 3, Volume 1, Item 2)
    - Bret Harte in California – A Character Study, Edgar Kahn, 1950 (Box 3, Volume 1, Item 3)
    - Louis Pasteur – His Achievements and Himself, Langley Porter, 1951 (Box 3, Volume 1, Item 4)
    - Don’t Sass the Upper Class, Murray Richards, 1951 (Box 3, Volume 1, Item 5)
      About social value of the rich; incl. handwritten discussion notes.
    - Was Tojo Murdered? William J. Kuder, 1951 (Box 3, Volume 1, Item 6)
    - A Very Short Story Of Trial By Jury, Judge Robert McWilliams, 1951 (Box 3, Volume 1, Item 7)
    - A Lyric Poet In An Iron Age, Robert M. Searls, 1952 (Box 3, Volume 1, Item 8)
    - Worlds In Collision, C. Donald Shane, 1952 (Box 3, Volume 1, Item 9)
    - Andrew S. Hallidie – A Forgotten San Francisco Personality, Edgar Kahn, 1952 (Box 3, Volume 1, Item 10)
    - On Being Elected, Osgood Murdock, 1952 (Box 3, Volume 1, Item 11)
    - Strange New World, Carl I. Wheat, 1952 (Box 3, Volume 1, Item 12)
    - Loyalty Oaths, Ben C. Duniway, 1953 (Box 3, Volume 1, Item 13)
    - On Tasting Wines, S.P. Lucia, 1953 (Box 3, Volume 1, Item 14)
    - Dinosaur Appraisal, Harold Bradley, 1953 (Box 3, Volume 1, Item 15)
    - Congressman Cox Investigates the Foundations, John F. May, 1953 (Box 3, Volume 1, Item 16)
    - How Free Is Our Press, Paul C. Edwards, 1953 (Box 3, Volume 1, Item 17)
    - The Have And The Have-Nots, Ira B. Joralemon, 1953 (Box 3, Volume 1, Item 18)
    - Fortifying the Mind With The Classics, Walter Morris Hart, 1953 (Box 3, Volume 1, Item 19)
    - Justice Holmes, The Huxleys And Moral Codes, Joseph T. O’Connor, 1954 (Box 3, Volume 1, Item 20)
    - Power – Electrical And Political, William B. Kuder, 1954 (Box 3, Volume 1, Item 21)
    - Man Alive, Langley Porter, 1954 (Box 3, Volume 1, Item 22)
    - The Privilege Against Self-Incrimination, Judge Robert McWilliams, 1954 (Box 3, Volume 1, Item 23)
    - Greek Tragedies And Modern Life, Edward L. Parsons, 1954 (Box 3, Volume 1, Item 24)
  - Chit Chat Essays, 1954-1956 (Box 3, Volume 2)
    Bound volume of typescripts, draft signed, reprints of essays and some misc.
    - Some Reflections On The Presidency, Edgar Eugene Robinson, 1950 (Box 3, Volume 2, Item 1)
    - On Politics And History, Edgar Eugene Robinson, 1952 (Box 3, Volume 2, Item 2)
    - Reasoning About The Values Of Education, Alexander Meiklejohn, 1953 (Box 3, Volume 2, Item 3)
    - Franklin D. Roosevelt, Edgar Eugene Robinson, 1954 (Box 3, Volume 2, Item 4)
    - Chit Chat’s 80th Birthday, Osgood Murdock, 1954 (Box 3, Volume 2, Item 5)
    - From My Library Shelves, Edgar Kahn, 1954 (Box 3, Volume 2, Item 6)
    - Ten Years With And Without The U.N. the Question Remains – 'Will The U.S. Default The U.N. To The Reds?' Lloyd D. Luckmann, 1954 (Box 3, Volume 2, Item 7)
    - The International Consequences Of Scientific Research, John B. Condliffe, 1954 (Box 3, Volume 2, Item 8)
    - Mapping The American West, Carl I. Wheat, 1955 (Box 3, Volume 2, Item 9)
      Published pamphlet.
    - Where There’s A Will, Ben C. Duniway, 1955 (Box 3, Volume 2, Item 10)
    - Some Biologic Implications Of Medical Research, Salvatore F. Lucia, 1955 (Box 3, Volume 2, Item 11)
    - Ars Piscatoria, Paul C. Edwards, 1955 (Box 3, Volume 2, Item 12)
    - Lost Valley, Harold C. Bradley, 1955 (Box 3, Volume 2, Item 13)
    - Malice In Wonderland, John B. May, 1955 (Box 3, Volume 2, Item 14)
    - Politics And Technology: Problems Of Independence And Interdependence, Harold H. Fisher, 1955 (Box 3, Volume 2, Item 15)
    - Opera For Opera’s Sake, Frank H. Sloss, 1955 (Box 3, Volume 2, Item 16)
    - Accounting For Taste, Murray Richards, 1955 (Box 3, Volume 2, Item 17)
    - No Longer Backward: The Problem Of Native Labor, Ira Joralemon, 1956 (Box 3, Volume 2, Item 18)
    - Oedipus, Walter Morris Hart, 1956 (Box 3, Volume 2, Item 19)
    - Some Aspects of Robert Louis Stevenson, Edgar Kahn, 1956 (Box 3, Volume 2, Item 20)
    - Political Freedom: Testimony On The First Amendment, Alexander Meiklejohn, 1956 (Box 3, Volume 2, Item 21)
    - Aristotle’s Poetics, William B. Kuder, 1956 (Box 3, Volume 2, Item 22)
    - How Far From The Sabine Farm? Osgood Murdock, 1956 (Box 3, Volume 2, Item 23)
    - The Maoris Of New Zealand, John B. Condliffe, 1956 (Box 3, Volume 2, Item 24)
    - Chit Chat Club 1874 to 1919, Charles A. Murdock, n. d. (Box 3, Volume 2, Item 25)
  - Chit Chat Club essays, 1887-1908 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Abigail Adams: On the Life and Character of a Woman, manuscript and typescript, Sheldon G. Kellogg, 1887 (Box 4, Folder 1, Item 1)
    - The Monroe Doctrine, A. F. Morrison, 1895 (Box 4, Folder 1, Item 2)
    - What the United States is Doing in the Philippines, typescript, 1902 (Box 4, Folder 1, Item 3)
    - James Russell Lowell, typescript, Sheldon G. Kellogg, 1890 (Box 4, Folder 1, Item 4)
    - Ideals of American Diplomacy, pamphlet, Eli T. Sheppard, 1903 (Box 4, Folder 1, Item 5)
    - William Ewart Gladstone, manuscript, Sheldon G.Kellogg, 1904 (Box 4, Folder 1, Item 6)
    - Recent Art Progress in the United States, manuscript, Sheldon G. Kellogg, 1906? (Box 4, Folder 1, Item 7)
    - Theodore Roosevelt, typescript, 1908 (Box 4, Folder 1, Item 8)
    - William Pitt Fosendeau[?] typescript, Sheldon G.Kellogg, 1908 (Box 4, Folder 1, Item 9)
  - Chit Chat Club essays, 1910-1912, 1942-1948 (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - 'Chinese' Gordon: The 19th Century Knight Errant, manuscript, Eli T. Sheppard, 1910 (Box 4, Folder 2, Item 1)
    - Camille Cavour, typescript, Sheldon G.Kellogg, 1910 (Box 4, Folder 2, Item 2)
    - The Sherman Antitrust Law, manuscript, Sheldon G.Kellogg, 1912 (Box 4, Folder 2, Item 3)
    - Frederick Ferdinand Low, Financier, Statesman, Diplomatist, 9th Governor of California, typescript, Eli T. Sheppard, 1916 (Box 4, Folder 2, Item 4)
    - Land of Promise -- How Fare Our Farmers: Footnotes on California Farmers’ Problems in a Changing World, typescript, Charles Murdock, 1942 (Box 4, Folder 2, Item 5)
    - Who’s Boss? Management Now and Tomorrow, typescript, Charles Murdock, 1944 (Box 4, Folder 2, Item 6)
    - What is a Dollar, typescript, Francis P. Farquhar, 1945 (Box 4, Folder 2, Item 7)
    - Organizing International Economic Cooperation: The Political Setting, typescript, John B.Condliffe, 1945 (Box 4, Folder 2, Item 8)
    - How Fervid the Church, typescript, Osgood Murdock, 1946 (Box 4, Folder 2, Item 9)
    - The Scientist and Society, typescript, C. Donald Shane, 1948 (Box 4, Folder 2, Item 10)
    - The Business Man in Post War America, typescript, Osgood Murdock (Box 4, Folder 2, Item 11)
    - Some Philosophical Reflections on the Law, typescript, Robert M. Searls, 1948 (Box 4, Folder 2, Item 12)
  - Chit Chat Club essays, 1950-1957 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Salesmen and Society, typescript, Osgood Murdock, 1950 (Box 4, Folder 3, Item 1)
    - The Have and the Have-Nots, typescript, Ira B. Joralemon, 1953 (Box 4, Folder 3, Item 2)
    - Man Alive, typescript, Langley Porter, 1954 (Box 4, Folder 3, Item 3)
    - The Musician of Bath, typescript, Ron Shane, 1954 (Box 4, Folder 3, Item 4)
    - Tissue Culture Cadences, typescript, Chauncey D. Leake, 1954 (Box 4, Folder 3, Item 5)
    - The International Consequences of Scientific Research, typescript, John B. Condliffe, 1954 (Box 4, Folder 3, Item 6)
    - Where There’s a Will, typescript, Benjamin Duniway, 1955 (Box 4, Folder 3, Item 7)
    - The Biologic Implications of Medical Research, typescript, Salvatore P. Lucia, 1955 (Box 4, Folder 3, Item 8)
    - Testimony of Harold C. Bradley, Elected President of the Sierra Club of California in 1957, before Congressional Committee in Washington, D. C., in April 1955, typescript (Box 4, Folder 3, Item 9)
    - Tom Frazer and the Building of the Lick Observatory, typescript, Ron Shane, 1955 (Box 4, Folder 3, Item 10)
    - Aristotle’s Poetics, typescript, William B. Kuder, 1956 (Box 4, Folder 3, Item 11)
    - The Suez Canal, typescript, John B. Condliffe, 1956 (Box 4, Folder 3, Item 12)
    - Woodrow Wilson, typescript, Edgar E. Robinson, 1957 (Box 4, Folder 3, Item 13)
    - Welfare Planning in the Bay Area, typescript, Benjamin Duniway, 1957 (Box 4, Folder 3, Item 14)
    - Like a Cigarette Should, typescript, Murray Richards, 1957 (Box 4, Folder 3, Item 15)
    - Courage as a Means to Peace, typescript, Lloyd Luckman, 1957 (Box 4, Folder 3, Item 16)
    - Shrine of the Ages Chapel, typescript, H.C. Bradley, 1957 (Box 4, Folder 3, Item 17)
  - Chit Chat Club essays, 1958-1960 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - What Pharaoh’s Daughter Started, typescript, Frank H. Sloss, 1958 (Box 4, Folder 4, Item 1)
    - Salting, typescript, Ira B. Joralemon, 1958 (Box 4, Folder 4, Item 2)
    - Oedipus and Jocasta, typescript, Walter Hart, 1958 (Box 4, Folder 4, Item 3)
    - Reflections on Loyalty, typescript, Edgar M. Kahn, 1958 (Box 4, Folder 4, Item 4)
    - John Peter Zenger, typescript, Paul Edwards, 1958 (Box 4, Folder 4, Item 5)
    - Rambles – Here and There, typescript, Harold C. Bradley, 1959 (Box 4, Folder 4, Item 6)
    - Twig Bending, typescript, Marchant, 1959 (Box 4, Folder 4, Item 7)
    - Fair is Foul, and Foul is Fair -- A Tale of Soiled Ermine and Draggled Plumes, typescript, Frank H. Sloss, 1960 (Box 4, Folder 4, Item 8)
    - What's in a Name? or The Irresistible Mean, typescript, Ira B. Joralemon, 1960 (Box 4, Folder 4, Item 9)
  - Chit Chat Club essays, 1960-1963 (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Reflections on Living One’s Life, typescript, Edgar M. Kahn, 1960 (Box 4, Folder 5, Item 1)
    - Bacon and Descartes, typescript, William B. Kuder, 1960 (Box 4, Folder 5, Item 2)
    - Thailand Trivia, typescript, Harold C. Bradley, 1961 (Box 4, Folder 5, Item 3)
    - Jim Crow – Whose Problem? typescript, John R. May, 1961 (Box 4, Folder 5, Item 4)
    - Gilbert and Sullivan in Retrospect, typescript, Frank H. Sloss, 1961 (Box 4, Folder 5, Item 5)
    - The Fourth ‘R’ – A Plea for Total Education, typescript, C. Julian Bartlett, 1962 (Box 4, Folder 5, Item 6)
    - A Tourist in Spite of Himself, typescript, Edgar M. Kahn, 1962 (Box 4, Folder 5, Item 7)
    - The Rise and Fall of Stalinism, typescript, Goothart (?), 1962 (Box 4, Folder 5, Item 8)
    - Deep Springs and Summerhill (Demonstrations in Education), typescript, William B. Kuder, 1963 (Box 4, Folder 5, Item 9)
    - Utopia, typescript, Harold C. Bradley, 1963 (Box 4, Folder 5, Item 10)
    - Thoughts from a Platform in Persepolis, typescript, Duce (?), 1963 (Box 4, Folder 5, Item 11)
  - Chit Chat Club essays, 1964-1966 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Mr. Justice Benjamin Nathan Cardoso, typescript, Edgar M. Kahn, 1964 (Box 5, Folder 1, Item 1)
    - Seek Not To Question, typescript, Frank H. Sloss, 1964 (Box 5, Folder 1, Item 2)
    - The Political Economy of Science, typescript, John B. Condliffe, 1964 (Box 5, Folder 1, Item 3)
    - A Christian’s View of the Racial Crisis, typescript, Dean C.J. Bartlett, 1964 (Box 5, Folder 1, Item 4)
    - The Problem of the Extended Ear, typescript, Judge Ben C. Duniway, 1964 (Box 5, Folder 1, Item 5)
    - The Use of Models in Physical Science, typescript, Joel H. Hildebrand, 1964 (Box 5, Folder 1, Item 6)
    - An Old Stamp Album, typescript, Ira B. Joralemon, 1964 (Box 5, Folder 1, Item 7)
    - Crisis at the University of California, typescript, Frank Gerbode, 1965 (Box 5, Folder 1, Item 8)
    - From Adam Smith to Keynes & After, typescript, John B. Condliffe, 1964 (Box 5, Folder 1, Item 9)
    - The Great American Intertie, typescript, William B. Kuder, 1965 (Box 5, Folder 1, Item 10)
    - Magna Carta: Was It? typescript, L.F.L. Pyman, 1965 (Box 5, Folder 1, Item 11)
    - Why Search and Research? typescript, Chauncey D. Leake, 1966 (Box 5, Folder 1, Item 12)
    - Practical Problems with a Family of Boys: A Case History 1908-1930, typescript, Harold C. Bradley, 1965 (Box 5, Folder 1, Item 13)
    - Europe in Retrospect, typescript, Edgar M. Kahn, 1966 (Box 5, Folder 1, Item 14)
    - Of Shoes and Ships and Sealing, typescript, Frank H. Sloss, 1966 (Box 5, Folder 1, Item 15)
    - Ethics and Power – The Shaping of Decision, typescript, Dean C.J. Bartlett, 1966 (Box 5, Folder 1, Item 16)
    - Student Revolt from the Standpoint of a College Trustee, typescript, Judge Ben C. Duniway, 1966 (Box 5, Folder 1, Item 17)
  - Chit Chat Club essays, 1967-1969 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - The Cows of India, typescript, Ira B. Joralemon, 1967 (Box 5, Folder 2, Item 1)
    - The Bent Twig, typescript, William B. Kuder, 1967 (Box 5, Folder 2, Item 2)
    - Nowhere – 400 years later. typescript, Harold C. Bradley (Box 5, Folder 2, Item 3)
    - Judah P. Benjamin: A Struggle Against Adversity, typescript, Edgar M. Kahn, 1968 (Box 5, Folder 2, Item 4)
    - Cryptology, manuscript, Henry K. Evers, 1968 (Box 5, Folder 2, Item 5)
    - The Rocky Road to the Courthouse, typescript, Frank H. Sloss, 1968 (Box 5, Folder 2, Item 6)
    - Auri Sacra Fames, typescript, John B. Condliffe, 1968 (Box 5, Folder 2, Item 7)
    - The Itch of Youth, typescript, Ira B. Joralemon, 1969 (Box 5, Folder 2, Item 8)
    - Changing Religion in a Changing Society, typescript, Dean C.J. Bartlett, 1969 (Box 5, Folder 2, Item 9)
    - Leadership in Higher Education: The Role of the Trustees – Should the Trustees Lead? typescript, Judge Ben C. Duniway, 1969 (Box 5, Folder 2, Item 10)
    - "…out of a void of darkness without sound..." typescript, John R. May, 1969 (Box 5, Folder 2, Item 11)
    - Portsmouth Plaza, typescript, Edgar M. Kahn, 1969 (Box 5, Folder 2, Item 12)
    - The Second Thinnest Book? typescript, Vincent Cullinan, 1969 (Box 5, Folder 2, Item 13)
  - Chit Chat Club essays, 1970-1971 (Box 8, Folder 1)